# **Marios Vottas**

Associate Data Scientist | MSc in Data Science

Highly motivated and ambitious. Trying to extract knowledge from every encounter. Currently acquiring knowledge on machine learning techniques and banking domain expertise by working closely with banking executives and machine learning senior specialists. Responsible for the maintenance of CI/CD Pipelines, trying to automate recurring tasks and develop advanced NLP projects. Skillful in Machine Learning, SQL. ETL and explaining technical procedures in not technical audience.

in Marios Vottas 🦪 Marios Vottas

# Experience

## Alpha Bank

Associate Data Scientist

2023/10 - Today

As a member of the Advanced Analytics team I:

- Develop churn prediction, segmentation, cross/up sell models and Ad Hoc analyses
- Develop complicated NLP projects
- Maintain and troubleshoot CI/CD pipelines
- Migrate existing jobs and stream into a cloud infrastructure

## IntTrust S.A.

Business Intelligence Engineer

2023/07 - 2023/09

Built Data Warehouse, ETL processes and reporting for clients in the banking and marine sectors

(SQL Server, SSIS, PowerBI)

### **Greek Army**

Soldier of Research and IT

2022/09 - 2023/06

HelpDesk, Sysadmin and Personnel training responsibilities

#### Education

#### **NCSR Demokritos**

MSc in Data Science

2021/10 -

Python | Machine Learning | Deep Learning | Big Data Management | Visualization

# **University of Peloponnese**

Informatics and Telecommunications

Bachelor of Science

2016/10 - 2021/10

#### **Soft Skills**

Adaptability Teamwork

Analytical Thinking Empathy

## **Technical Skills**

Machine Learning | Deep Learning | Python | NLP

SQL | NoSQL | SQL Server | SSIS

IBM CP4D | SPSS Modeler

## **Projects**

Drug to Drug Interaction Mutliclass Prediction Graph on Biomedical Literature Knowledge Graphs

Machine Learning using Graph Embeddings.

# **NLP Topic Discovery**

Topic discovery in Greek text using BERTopic and LDA.

## **Medical Image Classification**

Classification of chest X-Rays & Brain MRIs.

### Certifications

# 11 Udemy Courses (60+ Hours)

2023/10 - 2024/01

NLP | Deep Learning | MLOps

## **IBM Certifications (Predicta training)**

2023/10 - 2023/12

Certified in CP4D and SPSS Modeler

#### **Interests**

Sports (Football, Martial Arts, Padel ) | Reading Books

# Languages

Greek (Native) English (Fluent)